## JUNYI ZHANG

junyi42zhang@gmail.com ♦ GitHub ♦ junyi42.com

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests mainly lie in **computer vision**, **deep generative models**, and **representation learning**. I am now focusing on the **application of diffusion models**, exploring its potential for **both generation and perception scenarios**. I also have a background in action recognition, self-supervised learning, and modalities such as video, 3D, human motion, and language.

### **EDUCATION**

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Major in Computer Science and Technology; GPA: 3.92	Shanghai, China Sept. 2020 - Present
Zhiyuan College, Shanghai Jiao Tong University	Shanghai, China
Major in Zhiyuan Honors Program of Engineering (Top $5\%$ )	Sept. 2020 - Present

### SELECTED AWARDS

Microsoft Research "Stars of Tomorrow" Certificate (Top 10% interns)	2022
Huawei Fellowship (Top 1% in honors program)	2022
National Scholarship (Top 0.2% nationwide, highest honor in China)	2021
Undergraduate Merit Scholarship, A Level, SJTU (Top 1%)	2021

### **PUBLICATIONS**

A Tale of Two Features: Stable Diffusion Complements DINO for Zero-Shot Semantic Correspondence. Junyi Zhang, Charles Herrmann, Junhwa Hur, Luisa F. Polanía, Varun Jampani, Deqing Sun, Ming-Hsuan Yang. In submission to NeurIPS, 2023.

Layout Diffusion: Improving Graphic Layout Generation by Discrete Diffusion Probabilistic Models. Junyi Zhang, Jiaqi Guo, Shizhao Sun, Jian-Guang Lou, Dongmei Zhang. In ICCV, 2023.

### Bridging The Isolated Islands in Human Action Understanding.

Yong-Lu Li\*, Xiaoqian Wu\*, Xinpeng Liu, Yiming Dou, Yikun Ji, **Junyi Zhang**, Yixing Li, Xudong Lu, Jingru Tan, Cewu Lu. *Under review*, 2023.

Mining Cross-Person Cues for Body-Part Interactiveness Learning in HOI Detection.

Xiaoqian Wu\*, Yong-Lu Li\*, Xinpeng Liu, **Junyi Zhang**, Yuzhe Wu, Cewu Lu. *In ECCV*, 2022.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# University of California, Merced - Vision Learning Lab

Visiting Student – Supervisor: *Prof.* Ming-Hsuan Yang

Merced, California June. 2023 - Present

- Diffusion Models for Semantic Correspondence
  - Explore the internal representations of text-to-image diffusion models for semantic correspondence.
  - Discover the complementary of Stable Diffusion features and DINOv2 features, based on which achieve state-of-the-art performance under zero-shot setting on a variety of semantic correspondence benchmarks.
  - Paper submitted as first author to NeurIPS'23. More details at project page.

# Microsoft Research Asia - Data, Knowledge and Intelligence Group

Beijing, China July 2022 - Dec. 2022

Research Intern – Mentor: Dr. Shizhao Sun and Dr. Jian-Guang Lou

- Diffusion Models for Layout Generation, AI for Design Project
  - Study the application of diffusion models in graphic design, especially the graphic layout generation.
  - Develop discrete diffusion models specific to layout data, achieve state-of-the-art performance in unconditional and conditional generation tasks for several public layout datasets.
  - Paper accepted as first author to ICCV'23, with potential for product implementation.

### Shanghai Jiao Tong University - Machine Vision and Intelligence Group

Undergraduate Research Intern – Supervisor: Prof. Yong-Lu Li

Shanghai, China Oct. 2021 - Present

### • Unified Human Action Understanding Project

- Research on unifying multi-modal physical action spaces (2D, 3D, image, video, etc.) to a unified semantic space through the introduction of linguistic structure knowledge.
- Design and conduct experiments to extend our method on video datasets and verify the performance.

### • Human Action Knowledge Engine Project

- Study on improving Human-Object Interaction (HOI) detection by incorporating human action knowledge.
- Conduct experiments to examine the effect of image depth and multi-person interactions on HOI detection.
- Research results were submitted as co-author in two papers, one of which was accepted by ECCV'22.

### **SKILLS**

- Skills: Python (Pytorch), C/C++, html, css, Linux, LATEX, Assembly language
- Languages: English (TOEFL 105/120), Chinese (Native)